A Guide to the Ann Heidbreder Eastman Papers, 1978-1991
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Ann Heidbreder Eastman Papers, 1978-1991
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1991-053
8.4 cu. ft. 6 boxes
The collection consists of papers concerning Eastman's work as Virginia Tech's Faculty Publishing Officer, her work as Head of the Steering Committee for the Virginia Governor's Conference on Library and Information Services in 1991, and information on funding and support for libraries in Virginia. Materials in the collection date from 1978 to 1991.
Eastman, Ann Heidbreder
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Ann Heidbreder Eastman Papers were donated to Special Collections prior to 1991.
Biographical Note
Ann Heidbreder Eastman was a former resident of Blacksburg, Va., and worked as the University Faculty Book Publishing Committee's Publishing Staff Officer at Virginia Tech. She was married to Arthur H. Eastman, a former head of the university's English Department. Before coming to Blacksburg she worked at several New York publishing companies in editorial, sales, and marketing positions. She was active in many publishing and library organizations including, but not limited to the Association of American Publishers, the Women's National Book Association (WNBA), the American Library Association (ALA), the Center for the Book in the Library of Congress, and the National Book Committee.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of correspondence, publications, pamphlets, conference materials, newspaper clippings, and memoranda concerning Eastman's work as Virginia Tech's Faculty Publishing Officer, her work as Head of the Steering Committee for the Virginia Governor's Conference on Library and Information Services in 1991, and information on funding and support for libraries in Virginia. Materials in the collection date from 1978 to 1991.
Arrangement
The collection is separated into the following series: I. Virginia Tech University Libraries, II. Virginia State Library and Archives, III. American Library Association, and IV. Personal Papers. During processing in 2014-2015, folders were placed in series by the organization or individual to which they related. Within each series (or subseries), materials are arranged by related conferences/events/organizational units/activities.
Series I: Virginia Tech University Libraries has two subseries. Subseries A: Virginia Tech Faculty Book Publishing Committee, contains documents pertaining to faculty publications. Subseries B: Virginia Tech Libraries, focuses on university library administration, public relations, promotions, and library operations.
Series II: Virginia State Library and Archives contains papers related to the 1991 Virginia Governor's conference on Libraries and Information Services, Patrick County NEH application and reports, literacy information, and state and public library newspaper clippings.
Series III: American Library Association contains publications and pamphlets about the ALA and the San Antonia, Texas ALA annual meeting.
Series IV: Personal papers contains photographs and information concerning state and public library events.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Separated Materials
One publication was removed from collection and cataloged for the Special Collections Rare Book Collection: 1988-1989 Statistics of Virginia Public Libraries and Institutional Libraries.
Index Terms
Persons:
Eastman, Ann Heidbreder
Corporate Names:
American Library Association.; Library of Virginia.; Virginia State Libary and Archives.; Virginia State Libary.
Subjects:
Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; University History; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. University Libraries
Contents List
- Series I: Virginia Tech University Libraries
  - Subseries A: Virginia Tech Faculty Book Publishing Committee
    - Hill, Iris Tillman, Visit from UNC Press, April 13-14, 1987 (Box-folder 1-1)
    - General, 1984 - 1985 (Box-folder 1-2)
    - VT Faculty Book Publishing Committee, 1988 - 1989 (Box-folder 1-3)
    - Schedules and Lists, 1984 - 1985 (Box-folder 1-4)
    - VT Faculty Book Publishing Committee, 1983 - 1984 (Box-folder 1-5)
    - S. Adams and Ross, Thoreau (Box-folder 1-6)
    - Ariew: Dehum on Medieval Cosmology (Box-folder 1-7)
    - Arnold, Linda: Bureaucracy and Bureaucrats in Mexico City, 1742 - 1835 (Box-folder 1-8)
    - Bauer: Loch Ness (Box-folder 1-9)
    - Beyond Velikovsky: Analysis of a Public Controversy, by H.H. Bauer (Box-folder 1-10)
    - Bishop, L.: de Musset Manuscript (Box-folder 1-11)
    - Blieszner: Friendship in Adulthood (Box-folder 1-12)
    - Blalock: The Carnivalesque in in Robert Browning's, The Ring and the Book (Box-folder 1-13)
    - Bork, Dean R.: Methods of Evaluationand Design Studio Instruction (SCHEV Project), March 16, 1987 (Box-folder 1-14)
    - A Nammu and Arion Adventure, Brehony and Alderson (Box-folder 1-15)
    - Burch Brown (Box-folder 1-16)
    - John Cairns, Damaged Ecosystems (Box-folder 1-17)
    - John Crowell (Box-folder 1-18)
    - Drake (Box-folder 1-19)
    - Elgert, Klaus, Immunology (Box-folder 1-20)
    - Falco stories, novel, and poetry (Box-folder 1-21)
    - Fernandez (Box-folder 1-22)
    - Germana: The Feeling of Relativity (Box-folder 1-23)
    - Giles: Management of Wild Animals and Plants, October 1986 (Box-folder 1-24)
    - Goodsell, Charles (Box-folder 1-25)
    - Graham, Peter (Box-folder 1-26)
    - Herrick, Samuel: Astrodynamics, 1986 (Box-folder 1-27)
    - Hertzler, Ann, March 1987 (Box-folder 1-28)
    - Hoepner, Paul: Applied Microeconomic Analysis, March 1987 (Box-folder 1-29)
    - Holton: MBA Guide to Career Planning and Placement (Box-folder 1-30)
    - Hu Stephen, Stoppard (Box-folder 1-31)
    - Huggins (Box-folder 1-32)
    - G.B. Johnson (Box-folder 1-33)
    - Keegan/Patey Book, January 24, 1981 (Box-folder 1-34)
    - Kennedy, Charles: Nuclear Winter Conference, March 6, 1986 (Box-folder 1-35)
    - Galen Kline Manuscript (Box-folder 1-36)
    - Lynch, James: Henry Fielding and the Heliodoran Novel (Box-folder 1-37)
    - McCrumb, Sharyn (Box-folder 1-38)
    - McMullen, Judith: Various Projects (Box-folder 1-39)
    - Palmer: Photographs (Box-folder 1-40)
    - Payne, Al: Prayers (Box-folder 1-42, 1-43 (2 folders))
    - Poirier, Bures: Change of Custody (Box-folder 1-43)
    - Roane: Compendium of Rhododendron and Azalea Diseases (Box-folder 2-1, 2-2 (2 folders))
    - Saffle, Michael: Projects, December 1987 (Box-folder 2-3)
    - Savage, Lon:Thunder in the Mountains, Northcross Press Publisher (Box-folder 2-4)
    - Savage, Lon: Doug Wilder Book, 1987 (Box-folder 2-5)
    - VT University Press: Lon Savage, etc., Fall 1987 (Box-folder 2-6, 2-7 (2 folders))
    - Schetz, Katherine and Cassell: Talking Together: A Parents Guide (Box-folder 2-8)
    - Scigaj, Leonard: Ted Hughes (Box-folder 2-9)
    - Shallah, T (Box-folder 2-10)
    - Shumsky, N.L (Box-folder 2-11)
    - Simmons, Nancy: Mary Moody Emerson (Box-folder 2-12)
    - Solonevich, Inga: The Long Road to Solola (Box-folder 2-13)
    - Stipes, Jay (Box-folder 2-14)
    - Stump (Box-folder 2-15)
    - Taylor, Bernard: A Stain on the Water (Box-folder 2-16)
    - TFA: Hutchins and Vogler (Box-folder 2-16, 2-17, 2-18, 2-19 (4 folders))
    - TFA: Vogler (Box-folder 2-20, 2-21 (2 folders))
    - University Press of Virginia: Eastman duplicates (Box-folder 2-23, 2-24 (2 folders))
    - West, James, 1981 (Box-folder 2-25)
    - Wones: Memorial issue of American Journal of Science, eds. Sinha and Hewitt (Box-folder 2-26)
    - Worsham, Gibson: Projects, March 2, 1987 (Box-folder 2-27)
    - University Press fo America, Inc (Box-folder 3-5)
    - University of California Press (Box-folder 3-6)
    - Publishing Schedules (Box-folder 3-7)
    - Publishing Contracts (Box-folder 3-8)
    - Copyrights, 1981 (Box-folder 3-9, 3-10 (2 folders))
    - Association of American University Presses (Box-folder 3-11)
    - Meeting Minutes (Box-folder 3-12, 3-13 (2 folders))
    - Meeting Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 3-14)
    - Correspondence and Memos, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 3-15)
    - Desk Top Publishing, 1986 (Box-folder 3-16)
    - Electronic Publishing, January 1987 (Box-folder 3-17)
    - Publishing Institutes: Information and Letters (Box-folder 3-18)
    - General Information, January 1986 - June 1986 (Box-folder 3-19)
    - General Information, September 1985 - December 1985 (Box-folder 3-20, 3-21 (2 folders))
    - Department Heads Meeting, April 10, 1985 (Box-folder 3-22)
    - Journals (Box-folder 3-23)
    - ALA Publishing: CELJ (MLA) (Box-folder 3-24)
    - User's Guide: PRUCOMP (Box-folder 3-25)
    - Requests for Published Books (Box-folder 3-26)
    - Schedules and Lists, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 3-27)
    - Scholarly Communication, June 1985 (Box-folder 3-28)
    - Correspondence and Memos, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 3-29)
    - Meeting Minutes (Box-folder 3-30, 3-31 (2 folders))
    - Book Reviews, 1988 (Box-folder 3-32)
    - Meeting Minutes, May 6, 1988 (Box-folder 3-33)
    - Letters of Agreement and Corresponding Information (Box-folder 4-1)
    - Application for Subvention Forms - GC (Box-folder 4-2)
    - VT Faculty Book Publishing Committee, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 4-3, 4-4 (2 Folders))
    - Advance Book Information - ISBN, October 1986 (Box-folder 4-5)
    - Cataloging in Publication (Box-folder 4-6)
    - Jack Goellner Visit, John Hopkins Press, April 4-6, 1982 (Box-folder 4-7)
    - Joel Lee Visit, November 11-13, 1987 (Box-folder 4-8)
    - Tuchman, Barbara W. Proposed Visit #1, 1984 (Box-folder 4-9)
    - Tuchman, Barbara W. Schedule (Box-folder 4-10)
    - Tuchman, Barbara W. Proposed Visit #2, May 5-7, 1985 (Box-folder 4-11)
    - Tuchman, Barbara W. Budget (Box-folder 4-12)
    - Tuchman, Barbara W. Publicity (Box-folder 4-13)
    - Tuchman, Barbara W. Correspondence (Box-folder 4-14)
    - Tuchman, Barbara W. Pictures (Box-folder 4-15)
    - Tuchman, Barbara W. Duplicates (Box-folder 4-16)
  - Subseries B: Virginia Tech Libraries
    - Library Administrative Committee (Box-folder 2-28, 2-29 (2 folders))
    - Library Promotion Ideas (Box-folder 2-31, 2-32 (2 folders))
    - University Libraries: Miscellaneous (Box-folder 3-2)
    - Library Public Relations Task Force: Schedules (Box-folder 3-3)
    - Literacy Education Survey (Box-folder 4-17)
    - Public Relations Task Force Minutes (Box-folder 4-18)
    - Public Relations Plan, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4-19, 4-20 (2 Folders))
    - Strategic Plan, September 1986 (Box-folder 4-21)
    - Miscellaneous Papers (Box-folder 4-22)
    - Self Study, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 4-23)
    - Public Relations Campaign - General (Box-folder 4-24, 4-25 (2 Folders))
    - General Papers (Box-folder 4-26, 4-27 (2 Folders))
    - Library Development (Box-folder 5-1, 5-2 (2 Folders))
    - Library Faculty Association (Box-folder 5-3, 5-4 (2 Folders))
- Series II: Virginia State Library and Archives
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box-folder 2-30)
  - Board Appointment Papers (Box-folder 3-1)
  - Virginia Tech Visit, May 1, 1987 (Box-folder 3-4)
  - NEH Report on Patrick County: Continuity and Change in a Rural Community (Box-folder 5-5)
  - NEH Report on Patrick County: Appendices (Box-folder 5-6)
  - NEH Application - Patrick County, 1980 (Box-folder 5-7)
  - The Virginia Adult Literacy Initiative - Directory (Box-folder 5-8)
  - General Papers (Box-folder 5-9, 5-10 (2 Folders))
  - Miscellaneous Papers (Box-folder 5-11)
  - Virginia Governor's Conference on Libraries and Information Services
    - Governor's Conference on Libraries and Information Services, November 1990 (Box-folder 5-12)
    - Resolutions, 1990 (Box-folder 5-13)
    - General Papers, 1990 (Box-folder 5-14, 5-15 (2 Folders))
    - Observer Packet, November 10-11, 1990 (Box-folder 5-16)
    - Information Binder, November 10-11, 1990 (Box-folder 5-17, 5-18 (2 Folders))
    - Delegate Packet, November 10-11, 1990 (Box-folder 5-19)
    - Final Report, November 10-11, 1990 (Box-folder 5-20)
    - Notes and Minutes, April 1989 (Box-folder 6-1)
    - Notes and Minutes, May - December 1989 (Box-folder 6-2)
    - Notes and Minutes, January - April 1990 (Box-folder 6-3)
    - Notes and Minutes, May - June 1990 (Box-folder 6-4)
    - Notes and Minutes, August - October 1990 (Box-folder 6-5)
    - Notes and Minutes, November 1990 (Box-folder 6-6)
    - Notes and Minutes, December 1990 (Box-folder 6-7)
    - Notes and Minutes,1991 (Box-folder 6-9)
    - Personal Notes, 1990 (Box-folder 6-8)
    - Delegates and Committee Mailing Lists (Box-folder 6-10)
    - Publications (Box-folder 6-11)
    - Steering Committee Minutes and Papers (Box-folder 6-12)
  - White House Conference on Library and Information Services Taskforce (Box-folder 6-13, 6-14 (2 Folders))
  - Virginia Resolution 36 - Permanent Durable Paper Legislation, 1990 (Box-folder 6-15)
  - State and Public Library Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 6-16)
  - Virginia Library Association Publications (Box-folder 6-17, 6-18 (2 Folders))
  - Virginia Community and Census Data (Box-folder 6-19)
- Series III: American Library Association
  - Publications and Pamphlets (Box-folder 6-20)
  - San Antonio, Texas Meeting (Box-folder 6-21)
- Series IV: Personal Papers
  - Photographs (Box-folder 6-22)
  - Library Events (Box-folder 6-23)